MIKEL MATTICOLI

ENGINEER | PRODUCER | DESIGNER



ABOUT ME

Engineer, producer, and designer with a passion for helping good people and good tech work together. I have eight years of industry experience as a software engineer and technical director/project manager and enjoy working with diverse teams to solve complex problems and bring projects to completion.



mikel.matticoli@gmail.com



https://mikel.tech



Mative: English, Spanish; Proficient: French

EDUCATION

M.S. INTERACTIVE MEDIA

- ♦ Worcester Polytechnic Institute | 2022

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE B.S. INT. MEDIA & GAME DEV

- Minor in Robotics Engineering
- Minor in Media Art (Technical Art Focus)

SKILLS

Development Tools

- (Debian, RHEL, Arch)
- Web (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- NodeJS (ReactJS, Express, FireBase)
- Python (Flask, Socket.IO, Jupyter)
- Docker (Local Dev & PaaS)
- Google Cloud / Azure / AWS
- Nginx / Apache2 / Wordpress
- (Mobile) (Martin Unity 3D (VR/AR, PC, Mobile)
- ★ Unreal Engine (Blueprint, C++)
- C# (MS DEV204x Certified)
- Java (Android, Desktop, Enterprise)
- C/C++/Make/GDB
- MySQL/SQLite/MongoDB

Media Production Tools

- Microsoft Office Suite / G Suite
- Adobe Premiere / Video Editing
- Photoshop / GIMP (Image Editing)
- Reaper (SFX/Sound Editing/Mixing)
- 3D Printing / Laser Cutting
- Autodesk Maya (Model, Rig, Anim)
- Pixologic ZBrush (Sculpting)

Miscellaneous Skills

- Project Management (Agile / Scrum)
- Human-Centered Design (UI/UX)
- Professional Writing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT - BLOOMBERG LP

Jun 2018 - Present (Part-Time)

Dayton, NJ / Remote

I've built various tools to support infrastructure operation and engineering teams, working in small teams or individually to design and deploy these products end-to-end and deliver documentation and educational materials on my process and the tools themselves.

SENIOR FELLOW — INTENTIONAL DESIGN STUDIO

Sep 2019 - Present (Contract)

Worcester, MA / Remote

As a founding fellow, I helped to build the studio from the ground up. My team and I work with clients to design, build, and produce websites and apps that support and showcase academic research, products/services, or university events.

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR - JAZZ HISTORY DATABASE

Mar 2019 - Present (Part-Time)

Worcester, MA / Remote

Responsible for the JHDB's infrastructure, I provide support and training for both technical and non-technical audiences on various commercial, open-source, and in-house software solutions to support the online museum and ongoing archival work.

PROGRAMMER / TECH ARTIST - TRUMBUS GAMES

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021 (Part-Time)

Worcester, MA

Worked on a team of four to design, develop, market and release a successful comedy simulation PC game about a 1950s suburban housewife's battle against meddling eldritch horrors.

PROJECT MANAGER - THE GLOBAL LAB @ WPI

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020 (Part-Time)

Worcester, MA

I provided customized technical training & expertise as a consultant for student and faculty projects across all disciplines. I additionally developed, maintained, and documented the lab's software/hardware infrastructure, developing methods and training materials from scratch.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT - WPI IMGD + BOSE CORP.

Aug - Dec 2019 (Funded Research)

Worcester, MA

Working with IMGD/CS faculty at WPI to research use cases for spatial sound in consumer AR apps, I created a room-scale soundscape app using BoseAR + ARCore in Unity and presented at Bose HQ.

 $C O N T I N U E D (PG 1/2) \rightarrow$

AWARDS/EVENTS

EVENTS/COMPETITIONS

IMGD Showfest 2022 - Lead Organizer PAX East 2022 - WPI Exhibitor Booth Team Hack@WPI 2022 - Organizer/Mentor Hack@WPI 2021 - Best WPI Hack 2nd Place PAX East 2020 - Exhibitor (WPI Booth) MassDiGi Game Challenge '20 - Runner-Up VEX Worlds 2019 & 2021 - Innovate Award Hack@WPI 2019-21- Organizer/Git Expert HackForVenezuelaWPI '18 - Lead Organizer 2017 SB Entrepreneurial Fair - 1st Place HS MontyHacks 2017 - Best Educational Hack HackSBPL 2017 - Founder/Lead Organizer HackSBHS 2016 - Co-Founder/Organizer

ACADEMIC HONORS

- Teaching Assistant of the Year 2022
- MGD Excellence Award 2021
- WPI Two Towers Prize (H. Mention) 2021
- MGD Best MQP (People's Choice) 2021
- MGD Community Leader Award 2020
- Trovost MQP Award 2020
- Mard 2021 Interactive Qualifying Proj. Award 2021
- **8** Dean's List 2018-2021
- VEX Robotics Scholarship Award 2017-21
- WPI Unity Scholarship Award 2017-21
- 3x National HSF Scholar 2018-20

TOP PROJECTS

The Call of Karen

PC game about a 1980's housewife fighting Cthulhu (over 120,000 downloads on Steam). https://callofkaren.com

JHDB Global Contributor Portal

Accessible tool for the global jazz community to contribute historical artifacts to the JHDB. https://global.jazzhistorydatabase.com

Rigs of Color Website

Website/store showcasing work towards improving representation in media/games. https://rigsofcolor.com

See more projects on my website, these are just a few I enjoy talking about!

DATACENTER INF. OPS INTERN - BLOOMBERG LP

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017 (Part-Time)

Dayton, NJ

Independently performed hardware troubleshooting & workflow automation tasks. Developed internal web portal/REST API for monitoring and reporting on site-wide power usage. Utilized Agile/Scrum workflows in day-to-day work, balancing team and independent projects simultaneously.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN — SELFMADE CO.

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016 (Full-Time)

New York, NY

Implemented several major features for a custom CRM web app including Slack webhook integration, canned responses/autocomplete and mobile \mbox{UI} support. Gained proficiency with NodeJS Ecosystem, working with various technologies such as MeteorJS, ReactJS, and SCSS

IOS DEVELOPMENT INTERN — UPSWERVE INC.

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (Full-Time)

New York, NY

Added video capture and sharing features and numerous bug fixes for Snapchat-like iPhone app Camera Club. Attained proficiency with Git, NodeJS+SQL, iOS, and code review process under Google's code styling standards.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

ROBOTICS COACH - SOUTH BRUNSWICK SCHOOLS

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

South Brunswick, NJ

Provided instructional support and mentorship, and worked with school staff to coordinate finances and logistics for 6 teams of 10-20 students. Organized VEX Robotics Competition event as an event partner of RECF.

PROGRAMMER / TEAM LEAD — WPI ROBOTICS CLUB

Aug 2017 - Apr 2022

Worcester, MA

Project lead for VEX Artificial Intelligence Competition (research and software development). Managed budget and process purchase orders and expense reports for team supplies. Travel planning for a team of 15, including negotiating/booking flights, hotels, and rental vehicles.

CO-FOUNDER / SYSADMIN / TREASURER — IGDA WPI

Aug 2017 - Dec 2021

Worcester, MA

Helped plan and execute workshops to help club members develop game development and professional skills. Assisted with marketing and logistical planning, as well as securing funding for club meetings, workshops and game jams. Software and hardware maintenance of physical linux server hosting various services for chapter members

References available upon request

